# **Aaron Marr**

Software Engineer

**\** +44 7808 668 716

★ aaronmarr.co.uk

github.com/aaronmarr

# **Profile**

Front-End Developer with 10 years experience building websites and applications. Constantly strives for code quality, performance and maintainability. Enjoys a deep understanding of JavaScript, with a working knowledge of Python, Ruby and PHP. Currently learning Lisp (Racket and Clojure).

# **Work History**

## Front-End JavaScript Developer @ Headforwards

March 2019 - Present // Pool, UK (On Site)

- Write modern, performant and robust code for a suite of sites and applications
- Work with a variety of languages and frameworks including JavaScript, AngularJS, Vue, React, Eleventy and Python
- Refactor and modularise existing legacy code, ensuring JavaScript components are testable and follow modern coding standards
- Refactor legacy Bootstrap CSS using Tailwind, improving architecture and reducing file sizes by orders of magnitude
- Improve local development workflows using Docker
- Communicate and collaborate with an agile, multi-disciplinary product development team on a daily basis

#### Senior Web Developer @ Colateral

April 2017 - March 2019 // Redruth, UK (Part Remote)

- Develop a large-scale Software-as-a-Service product using React and Redux
- Write clean, scalable CSS using Sass and BEM
- Roll-out a unit test suite using Mocha and Enzyme
- Build services and APIs using Node.js and Django
- Work as part of a small, cross-functional team in a start-up environment

#### Front-End Developer @ Torchbox

April 2016 - April 2017 // Bristol, UK (Fully Remote)

- Build bespoke Front-Ends for Django and Drupal websites using HTML5, Sass and JavaScript (ES6)
- Promote, and lead on, style-guide driven development using PatternLab
- Implement modular Sass architectures using BEM and ITCSS methodologies
- Develop custom JavaScript libraries using ES6 and Babel Starter Kit

#### Front-End Developer @ Freelance

October 2015 - April 2016 // Redruth, UK (Fully Remote)

- Consult and advise on Front-End Sass and HTML5 template architectures
- Promote component-driven development using a range of Front-End frameworks
- Create custom, white-label Twitter Bootstrap themes
- Rapid prototyping using Ruby on Rails

## **UX/UI Developer** @ Dewsign

July 2015 - October 2015 // Falmouth, UK (On Site)

- Lead on Front-End development for websites built using WordPress
- Develop custom WordPress themes and plugins
- Improve development workflows using Docker

#### **Skills**

# **Programming Languages**

JavaScript (ES6), Python, Ruby, PHP, HTML5, Sass, CSS

#### Libraries and Frameworks

React, Redux, Vue, Vuex, Angular, Gatsby, Eleventy, Tailwind, Ruby on Rails, Django, Express, Koa, D3, jQuery

#### **Tools and Platforms**

Emacs, Git, Docker, Linode, Heroku, MacOS, Linux, Sketch, InVision

#### Design

Typography, grids, Design Systems, wireframes, prototypes

#### **Education**

Education

# **Falmouth University**

Sept 2013 - Sept 2014 Postgraduate Certificate in Higher

# Falmouth University

Oct 2007 - June 2010 Bachelor of Arts in Digital Media

#### **University of East Anglia**

July 2006 - July 2007 Foundation Degree in Computing

# **Volunteering**

#### **Code Club**

2017

Run a Code Club (part of Raspberry Pi Foundation) for 11 to 12 year olds, including sessions on Scratch, Python, and event-driven programming using JavaScript

# **Work History (continued)**

## **UX/UI Developer @ Headforwards**

October 2014 - July 2015 // Pool, UK (On Site)

- Front-End Development using JavaScript (Backbone), HTML5 and Sass
- Design key interface elements, using wireframes and interactive prototypes
- Unit testing using Mocha and Chai

# **Learning Information Designer @ Falmouth University**

July 2012 - September 2014 // Falmouth, UK (Part Remote)

- Front-End development using HTML5, JavaScript (jQuery) and Sass
- UX/UI design, including wireframes, story boards and interactive prototypes
- Responsive web design

## Learning Technologist (Intern) @ Falmouth University

September 2011 - July 2012 // Falmouth, UK (Part Remote)

• Web design and development for a range of internal systems and websites

#### **Other Interests**

#### **Down time**

Music, Craft Ale, Single Malt Whisky, family time, walks, Cornwall